Chad Hatala

Knoxville, Tennessee, United States



chad.hatala@gmail.com



865-809-8214



linkedin.com/in/chad-hatala

Summary

As a Senior Security Engineer with several certifications, I have over eight years of experience in the cybersecurity field, working across various industries such as retail, law, and healthcare. My core competencies include cybersecurity program implementation, threat hunting and research, consultancy and advisory services, metrics dashboards and reporting, intelligence collection and analysis, email security solutions, process optimization and creation, and policy development and compliance.

Experience



Senior Security Engineer

Provisions Group

Nov 2022 - Jun 2023 (8 months)

Served as a security engineer and information security consultant responsible for evaluating network vulnerabilities, identifying security gaps, and collecting both intelligence and operational data. Leveraged SharePoint as a central platform for data management and reporting on information security operations, in addition to metrics provided by Sentinel and Defender. Additionally, I generated best-inclass intelligence reports and presentations for top-level executives. Furthermore, I actively participated in the Security Working Group, contributing to the identification and resolution of security weaknesses throughout the organization. Leveraged training materials to create an internal security awareness platform for training purposes and served as ProofPoint liason.



Consulting Information Technology Specialist

Freelance

Jan 2017 - Nov 2022 (5 years 11 months)

Contracted Information Security and Technology services for Healthcare and Legal Professionals. Consulted and ensured compliance with HIPAA, NIST, PCI-DSS and other frameworks. Drove technology advancements to enhance security and efficacy of healthcare and legal operations. Served as a 24/7 SME to provide technical support in addition to incident response and mitigation services.

Director of Information Security, Cybersecurity Analysis and Research

Threds, Inc.

Jul 2019 - Oct 2022 (3 years 4 months)

Lead organizational efforts in protecting information assets, managing cybersecurity risks, ensuring compliance and developed a secure environment. Provided security awareness training, strategic direction, policy development, procedures, incident management and collaborated with stakeholders to establish a security program that aligns with business objectives.

Data Protection Officer

Threds. Inc.

Jul 2018 - Oct 2022 (4 years 4 months)

Served as the organizations Data Protection Officer, in this role my responsibilities included ensuring the privacy and safety of customer data, fulfillment of deletion requests, and the monitoring and maintenance of privacy compliance across the enterprise.

Cyber Threat Hunter

Threds, Inc.

Jun 2014 - Oct 2022 (8 years 5 months)

Trained staff on information security awareness and digital safety techniques. Matched IoC's with Mitre&ATTCK, VirusTotal, and other knowledge bases. Created incident reports for C-Suite and stakeholders.

Cloud Engineer

Threds, Inc.

Jul 2013 - Oct 2022 (9 years 4 months)

Proven ability to lead and implement technology, security and process improvements that reduce costs, and increase efficiency, security posture and consumer confidence. Through several ongoing projects, process changes, marketing implementations and more helped reach a million-dollar-a-year store in 2019. The store is projected to cross the \$2 million dollar mark + for the second time in 2022. Maintained 30+ eCommerce-based fulfillment stores across the enterprise. Provided security oversight for third-party vendors and worked with stakeholders to mitigate vulnerabilities and remediate existing gaps.

Ramp Supervisor

QuickFlight Services

Jan 2008 - Jul 2009 (1 year 7 months)

Ensured smooth and efficient operation of ground handling services; oversaw AO activities and coordinated ramp team to maintain safety, timeliness and adherence to airline, airport and FAA regulations. Participated and aided in the training of ramp members on aircraft security and procedures in addition to emergency response planning.

Education



University of Colorado Colorado Springs

Specialization, Homeland Security and Cybersecurity Jan 2023 - Jun 2023

https://coursera.org/verify/specialization/BHCMJBSFGR86

University of Colorado Colorado Springs

Specialization, Computer Security and Systems Management

Jan 2023 - Jul 2023

https://coursera.org/verify/specialization/MWZ8V624FVX5

Pellissippi State Community College

Computer Information Technology / Cyber Defense Concentration Aug 2020 - May 2022

Pellissippi State Community College

Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources Design 2008 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications

- Penetration Testing, Incident Response and Forensics IBM https://www.credly.com/go/8WNmRQxO
- IBM Cybersecurity Analyst Professional Certificate IBM NAHWKNDAJK5A
- **UI / UX Design Specialization** California Institute of the Arts VPWZWE4B84A9
- **Я говор ю по- р усски** Tomsk State University 5EGHTFFCTY3T
- Cybersecurity Compliance Framework & System Administration IBM https://www.credly.com/go/p26frNh5
- Network Security & Database Vulnerabilities IBM https://www.credly.com/go/ZqBNCKI6
- SOC Level I TryHackMe
 THM-RD1IGAA2P0
- Cyber Defense TryHackMe
 THM-TWLX8OUKCN
- Malware Analysis and Introduction to Assembly Language IBM 4BDNBK99366D
- Ethical Hacking Essentials (EHE) EC-Council 9SHBQ9CCPW3C
- Systems Security Certified Practitioner (SSCP) (ISC)² UFD2HVE7HB3Y
- Russian History: from Lenin to Putin University of California, Santa Cruz

8N9QSR35M93E

Security Awareness Training - (ISC)²
S4AKYMAL 5W42

Cybersecurity Leadership and Management - Infosec 42YLMPR4PHUK

Splunk Search Expert - Splunk L6NUT4LY5SGP

- Palo Alto Networks Cybersecurity Professional Palo Alto Networks 5TE679N3GSWZ
- **101 Critical Infrastructure Protection (Public)** U.S. Department of Homeland Security 8538b981661a74b1d89bd383c3f4cd52
- **101 Reverse Engineering (Public)** U.S. Department of Homeland Security 8538b981661a74b1d89bd383c3f4cd52
- Cloud Computing Security (Public) Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency
 1fc9cafdf3ab0dd561630d303b6e9bb7
- Cyber Intelligence (Public) Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency c55d17c5d48e1ed528a2eecd6cb61df4
- Blockchain Security Infosec
 M8BNVUEK9KE2
- Certified in Cybersecurity (CC) (ISC)²
 YRVV7WU8Y93K
- Project Management University of Colorado Boulder ZRRSFHG37SQ5
- Diploma in Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP 2019) Alison
 2157-32174849

IBM Certified Data Science - IBM

QNVUC8UPV3D3

- Google Cloud Digital Leader Google Career Certificates
 AE6K8XKPFWTN
- Google Professional Workspace Administrator Google Career Certificates 2KJRUFZFMTD6
- Google Cybersecurity Professional Google Career Certificates
 RKJ7L58SMVZR

Skills

Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing (VAPT) • Microsoft Defender • Information Security Consulting • Project Management • IBM QRadar • IBM Cognos Analytics • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • SQL • Jupyter • Data Mining